# **DIOMIDES MAVROYIANNIS**

TECHNICALLY ASTUTE ECONOMIST WITH INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

+33 695669809 | dmavroyiannis8@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/diomavro French and Cypriot

February 10th, 2022

To whom it may concern,

#### R220712 Blackrock

I am writing to you to express my interest in joining Blackrock as a Junior Data Analytics Specialist with Python.

I am Ph.D. economist with diverse experience conducting credit analysis, reviewing, researching, and managing data, and developing models. In my current position, as the financial advisor in corporate reporting and financial analysis at one of the largest oil producers, it is my function to forecast the effects of monthly FOREX fluctuations on earnings per segmentation. My role also involves aggregating and analyzing data for all the downstream UK and Nordic refineries and entails advising on capacity utilization and presenting these to management.

Throughout my experience, I have gained strong analytical and communication skills. I have received formal econometrics education, which included a heavy emphasis on time-series analysis, up to GARCH and Vector autoregressive modeling. My academic path has also allowed me to delve further into econometrics with a heavier emphasis on the Method of Moments and I later published work on Ergodic theory in economics in 'Decision Analyses', which uses Geometric Brownian motion as dynamic to infer discount rates.

Further enriching my quantitative background, I have learned to apply all of the above using programming techniques. I am currently also the module leader in Econometrics at the Milestone institute where teach students how to apply statistical analysis in Python and R. These experiences have helped me improve not only my programming skills but also my ability to communicate complex ideas and sharpened my leadership skills.

I am unafraid of public speaking, and I am fluent in three languages, including French and English. As a third culture kid, I grew up between Paris and New York, with a little detour via Dublin, Brussels, Brighton, Edinburgh, and now Budapest. My international background has shaped me into an adaptive character who can easily integrate with different cultures and has also allowed me to cultivate my problem-solving skills.

All of the above is to say that I believe I have the foundational skills and knowledge that are easily transferable to the position of Data Analytics Specialist at Blackrock. My background and targeted expertise can support the company's senior analyst in providing analytical reasoning in committees and discussion within the team, and to act proactively toward the resolution of issues as part of one of the world's leading credit rating companies.

Both my academic and professional experiences have been fruitful and rewarding but I am now eager for more challenges by joining the Blackrock team of intellectually curious and innovative professional specialists.

Please find my CV attached and do not hesitate to contact me should you inquire further information.

Yours faithfully, **Diomides Mavroyiannis** 

# **DIOMIDES MAVROYIANNIS**

TECHNICALLY ASTUTE ECONOMIST WITH INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

+33 695669809 | dmavroyiannis8@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/diomavro French and Cypriot

Doctorate in Economics with proven experience (over 1 billion euros in value added) and strong practical experience in financial analysis, data analysis and forecasting. Academic background focused on the economics of innovation and pricing using growth maximizing techniques.

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

## UNIVERSITE PARIS DAUPHINE

Doctorate in Economics - 2019

- Specialised in industrial organisation, microeconomics and Ergodic economics.
- Thesis focused on the economics of innovation and pricing of intellectual property using growth maximization techniques.
- Doctoral courses in Incentive Mechanism Theory, Advanced Microeconomics, Cooperative Game Theory and History of Economic Thought.
- Published paper: 'Microfoundations of discounting' in Decision Analysis.

#### UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH

MSc in Economics - 2015

- Deepening of technical knowledge in econometrics, micro/macroeconomics and time series. Case studies applied to issues of corporate strategy, investments and mergers-acquisitions.
- Thesis: What is the effect of technology on wages? The main findings are that, as long as humans have the edge on some sectors, the cost disease entails higher overall wages.

# UNIVERSITY OF DURHAM

MSc in International Finance - 2013

- Study of international finance and corporate governance practices alongside econometric techniques for finance and asset pricing (Black Scholes/VAR); international trade and monetary theory.
- Summer school in Cologne. Contributed to a study on the impact of Brazilian tax rates on DHL's supply chains.

#### UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX

BSc Finance - 2012

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# ExxonMobil, Budapest

CORPORATE REPORTING ADVISOR - 08.21 - PRESENT

- Manage reporting units in Norway and UK. Responsible for sales figures and their presentation to management.
- Creation of "tableau" dashboards to automate data processing from SAP to DATAFLEX
- Responsible for the Forex effects on the European region's profits.
  Oversight and innovation of transactional and translational processes for all European revenues.

# Milestone Institute, Budapest

MODULE AND ECON-COHORT LEADER - 08.21 - PRESENT

- Lecturer in Industrial Organization and Econometrics
- Mentor: personalized follow-up, deepening of knowledge and skills for each student, organization of a reading and debate workshop.

# Schuman Associates, Brussels European Economics, Paris

ECONOMIC CONSULTANT - 01.20 - PRESENT

- Counterfactual scenario studies (with and without government subsidies) based on NPV and WACC of innovative projects led by companies in the energy sector (electricity, gas, hydrogen).
- Scale optimization of projects benefiting from government subsidies.
  Grants ranging from 55M € for SMEs to 600M € for multinationals.
- Writing of reports for the European Commission supporting applications for IPCEI grants by European energy companies.
- Prepared the portfolio of numerous projects including market analysis before and post intervention.

## Université Paris Dauphine, Paris Université Marne-la-Vallée, Paris

TEACHING ASSISTANT - 2015 - 2019

- Lecturer: Economics of Uncertainty (VnM, Bayesian, insurance, etc) L3 in Mathematics; General Equilibrium L2 in Mathematics; Microeconomics L1 in Economics.
- Lecturer: Monetary Economics (central banking, interest rates, monetary aggregates); Social and Economic Policies (unemployment, taxation) L2 in Economics.
- Chief librarian for the MSc and PHD library

#### LOGICOM GROUP, Nicosia

CREDIT ANALYST - 2013 - 2014

• Evaluation of credits and associated risks (regressions, probabilistic models). Analysis of the company's internal data and presentations to the economic director and financial analysts.

#### Council of the EU, Brussels

MULTI-ANNUAL FINANCIAL FRAMEWORK ANALYST - 2012 - 2013

- Assisted in the creation of the first draft of a MFF compromise to meet the diverse demands of numerous European Union member states.
- Researched and analysed the effectiveness of various policies, especially direct payment versus conditional payments and the European cohesion fund and it's thresholds.

# **DIOMIDES MAVROYIANNIS**

TECHNICALLY ASTUTE ECONOMIST WITH INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

+33 695669809 | dmavroyiannis8@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/diomavro French and Cypriot

#### IT SKILLS

EXCEL (VBA) | MATHEMATICA | PYTHON STATA | R | EVIEWS | TABLEAU | SAP

## **LANGUAGES**

FRENCH, ENGLISH, GREEK - FLUENT HUNGARIAN- LEVEL 1

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Speaker: University of Cyprus Economics Seminar, Cyprus - 2019

Speaker: Public Economic Conference, France - 2019

Speaker: Spain-Italy-Netherlands Meeting on Game Theory (SING15), Finland- 2019

Attendee: Real World Risk Institute, New York, USA - 2019

• An intensive workshop run by Nassim Nicholas Taleb which focuses on the statistical properties of fat tails.

Speaker: BiGSEM Workshop in Economic Theory, Germany - 2018

Attendee: NEComplex Systems Institute Summer School, Boston, USA - 2018

• A summer school at MIT run by Yaneer Bar Yam which focuses on complexity science. Included two projects: the first was a python program which could randomly generate fractals of different kinds and the second, also a Python project was about representing communication dynamics on a network with agents who reinforce their opinions by sharing similar information.

Participant: Durham Trading competition, UK - 2012

• A program run over a semester at Durham where masters students compete to get the best outcomes on a trading account. I won 2nd place among around 200 participants, this was partially evaluated using the Sharpe Ratio.

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES AND INTERESTS

- Various international experiences:
  - English-French translator in China;
  - Cooperation with the Lebanese teams of Logicom in the creation of a marketing software
  - Military service in Cyprus.
- Avid reader in philosophy and history.

### REFERENCES UPON REQUEST

- Anthoulis Papachristoforou Group CFO at Logicom Public LTD
  - o a.papachristoforou@logicom.net
- David Ettinger Professor of Economics, Laboratoire d'Economie de Dauphine
  - o david.ettinger@dauphine.psl.eu
- Frédéric Loss Senior Lecturer, Laboratoire d'Economie de Dauphine
  - o frederic.loss@dauphine.psl.eu